#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/jimcarey (LinkedIn)

## Top Skills

IT Service Management Service Management ITIL

## Languages

French

# Jim Carey

Head of Regional Technology

Malaysia

# Summary

Senior IT Leader with 21 years of experience across a broad suite of disciplines, including: Service Management, Service Delivery, IT Operations, Platform Engineering, Infrastructure & Datacentre Management, Application Development & Support, Business Continuity Management, Call Centre Operations, Process Re-Engineering, Project/Programme Management, and Digital Transformation/Change Adoption. Currently heading the regional technology team of a Tier 1 insurance company in Asia.

## Experience

Prudential Services Asia 10 years

Head, Regional Technology October 2017 - Present (4 years 3 months) Malaysia

Heading delivery of a diverse set of IT services across the Asia Pacific region, including full-suite Infrastructure & Operations Management, Service Management & Service Delivery, Digital Transformation, and Software & Platform Engineering.

#### I.T. Director

January 2012 - Present (10 years)

Cyberjaya, Malaysia

Responsible for IT services provided by a centralised hub to businesses across the Asia Pacific region, including Service Desk / Service Support, Service Management, Batch Operations, PMO, Datacentre Management, Release Management, Strategic Procurement, and Disaster Recovery / Business Continuity Management.

Standard Chartered Bank

11 years 1 month

Head, IT Service Centre November 2007 - January 2012 (4 years 3 months)

Page 1 of 2

Providing strategic and general management to a multi-skilled global IT Service Centre.

Disciplines included Service Desk, Incident Management, Problem Management, Change Management, Security Administration, Request Coordination and Fulfilment, Datacentre Operations, Technical Support, Asset & License Management, Service Reporting.

Senior Service Manager, Wholesale Bank (Transaction Banking) September 2004 - October 2007 (3 years 2 months)

Responsible for global end-to-end Service Management of all production technology services used by SCB's Wholesale Bank Transaction Banking businesses (Cash Management, Trade Services, Commercial Loans).

Re-Engineering and Transition Project Manager January 2001 - August 2004 (3 years 8 months)

Part of a core team to provide subject matter expertise and project management for an IT Services re-engineering project at Standard Chartered, consolidating, standardising, and centralising disparate country-based functions (Incident, Problem, Change & Equest Management, Security Management, Automated Event Management) into two global Service Centres in KL, Malaysia and Chennai, India. This involved process and solution design, tool assessment and functional definition, resource profiling and recruitment, facilities fit-out, training, and finally transition management of 50+ countries into the IT hubs.

## Education

Cardiff University / Prifysgol Caerdydd BA, English Literature · (1993 - 1996)

King Edward VI Five Ways (1985 - 1992)